and we're live on YouTube welcome
everybody to our second anti-spy bill
event I think in a few moments we will
be simulcasting on Facebook so hello in
New Zealand and hello to the world
tonight we have with us again the
awesome Kim comm we also have with us
CIA whistleblower John Kiriakou
but before we hear from those guys we're
just going to catch up a little bit on
what's happened since the last of it and
what we'll be doing going forward so the
last event was a massive success which I
am personally really pleased about we
had put out three press releases to New
Zealand media they chose not to cover
the event but despite that within a
couple of hours of it we had achieved
3.3 million Twitter impressions we had
reached half a million people on
Facebook and we had about 10,000 live
viewers which is really incredible for
an event that was just purely spread by
word of mouth
we had no marketing budget no
corporations or governments behind us
and we did it ourselves together so
congratulations to everyone for that
after that amazing turnout our press
releases have now been picked up by New
Zealand media on Friday
two days ago news hub which is a major
New Zealand media outlet published an
article about our event tonight and it
got over 2,000 shares in under 24 hours
since them The Daily Dot has also picked
it up and published two there two and a
half million Facebook followers and we
are now live also on the daily blog
photo indeed which is one of the biggest
and most significant political blog
sites in New Zealand so at the last
event I told you that we were going to
hear from activists from all of the five
countries we got through Australia and
the United States and the UK and New
Zealand but we miss Canada because of
some technical issues so tonight we're
going to start out by hearing from
Bailey LeMond
so as president of the pirate party in
Canada she sent us a video message about
how the same types of legislation that
we've been subjected to in New Zealand
have also been inflicted upon the
Canadian public so Joe awesome kick
manager is going to go ahead and play
her message for you now hi everyone my
name is Barry LeMond I'm an activist I'm
the president of The Pirate Party of
Canada and I'm also the vice chairwoman
of pirate parties international so I
live in Canada and Canada is part of the
five eyes alliance so here's a little
bit about our situation up here so up
until 1984 the Royal Canadian Mounted
Police also known as the RCMP after
there's not only a police service but as
an intelligence agency that had the
power to both spy on people and enforce
the law long story short this is very
very bad they did terrible things and in
1984 the McDonald Commission was
launched this was an investigation into
the crimes of the RCMP which resulted in
the creation of CSIS or the Canadian
security and intelligence service which
is Canada's main spy agency to this day
stopped forward to 2015 the
anti-terrorism Act also known as bill
c-51 became law under Prime Minister
Stephen Harper's Conservative government
this law is still in place c-51 it was
widely opposed across the country it
still is and it's not only seen as
problematic by activists but by many of
the spies themselves and former spies
who have come out and said how truly
awful this law is Canada's
anti-terrorism act not only gives our
various police forces and spy agencies
the power to store our information our
data and share that information about us
with one another freely but it allowed
surfaced which is not a law enforcement
agency to preemptively detain people who
haven't even committed any crimes but
are seen as threats to national security
based on reasonable suspicion so things
like what you say online if you're
spreading terrorist propaganda
whatever that is right um the thing is
this law doesn't even define what any of
these things really mean leaving it open
for anyone to be targeted and locked up
for their speech for their ideas and
that's just completely unacceptable I
think we all agree on that but some now
today we do have a new government in
power the Liberal Party
unfortunately they fully supported bill
c-51 from the beginning however they
have promised to reform it right now
that's what they're supposedly working
on however none of the proposed reforms
seem to address the most problematic
elements of this law that I just
described to you on Parliament vote for
the summer so it's going to be a few
weeks before they get back to it so
we'll see what happens but right now it
still stands um I think we can all agree
that state surveillance is completely
incompatible with democracy and that
free speech does not exist in a country
where the spies and the law enforce and
the law enforcement people are given
enough power to literally take anything
you say as a threat to national security
which is what we have here in Canada and
from what I understand it's what the
other five wise countries have - it's
important to keep in mind that
surveillance is first and foremost an
issue of power where the powerful get to
invade our privacy to uphold their power
through their political system and
criminalize anyone who speaks out or
fights back this is why events like this
where the public gets to join together
to create policies that favor privacy
for the average citizen and transparency
for the state are so crucial as all of
us move forward in our respective
countries so big thank you to Susie and
the internet party for this amazing
initiative thank you so much for that
Bailey that's really awesome it's been
great to hear from activists in each of
the five countries so my big piece of
news is that we've decided that we are
going to continue these events
ongoing so we're going because we're an
election season and we're going
have about six weeks to go five six
weeks ago we are actually going to hold
this event every Sunday night for the
foreseeable future to continue to work
on the the draft copy of the engines
Bible together with all of you and then
we have been discussing an action plan
for the next twelve or so months beyond
that I will tell you a bit more about
that later on in the program but for now
I want to move here and have us hear
from John so just quickly going to read
you a little thing I wrote about John
today and then obvious for the daily
book CIA torch of whistleblower John
Kerry aku was recruited from the high
school that he taught jared leto at in
the decades to follow he traveled the
world recruited other spies and turned
and oversaw operations that captured
al-qaeda militants and sent them to
Guantanamo Bay eventually I trained to
keep secrets
there was one he could not live with his
government was torturing people
eventually he shared what he knew with
his fellow countrymen but tonight he
will share it with New Zealand and the
world so John please please away tell us
your story because all the messages that
you have to give thank you so much for
having me for doing this for giving me
the opportunity the soapbox Amanda to do
it and I'll apologize for the lighting
it's a I had every light on in my in my
room and it's still a I fear not light
enough there anyway I'm you're right I
was I was recruited into the CIA when I
was in graduate school I was teaching
high school at the time at a private
school in Washington DC and
as it turned out my graduate school
adviser was a CIA officer undercover as
a graduate school advisor and he was the
one who recruited me into the agency I
had never really considered the CIA but
I was getting ready to graduate and I
didn't have a job I was getting married
soon after graduation I really needed
the work and the idea of seeing the
world was exciting to me and so I said
sure I'll go through the process so I
did I went through the process got hired
started on the first of January 1990 and
started working as an analyst so really
I was sitting in a cubicle thinking the
big thoughts writing writing papers for
the president the vice-president the
secretaries of state and defense the
national security adviser and that was
great it was a lot of fun for a while
and then I got bored went overseas that
also as an analyst to the Middle East
learned to speak Arabic and then went
back to headquarters again in 1997 again
I was bored and so into not not 2000 in
1998 I made a very unusual switch from
analysis to counterterrorism operations
and and went overseas as a as an
Operations Officer like actually trying
to infiltrate terrorist groups and
either disrupt future attacks or break
up the group and found that I had a
knack for it it was dangerous certainly
but it was interesting it was fun it was
important and so I decided well maybe I
found my my place my niche I went back
to CIA headquarters after serving
overseas in 2000 and
September 11th hit in 2001 that changed
everything at the CIA as it turned out
the CIA after 2001 returned to its roots
the CIA that I had come of age in was
not the real CIA the real CIA was one
that that requires great oversight and
one that that is constantly pushing the
bounds of morals and ethics and legality
but I was as angry as every other
American on September 11th and I
volunteered certainly a good Afghanistan
and fight or do whatever was necessary
what I ended up doing was I was sent to
Pakistan as the chief of CIA
counterterrorism operations there and it
was in that job that in early 2002 I led
a series of raids that resulted in the
capture of Abu Zubaydah whom the CIA
believes at the time was the number
three in al-qaeda and many dozens I'm
not allowed to say the exact number but
many dozens of al-qaeda fighters at and
safe houses all over Pakistan well I had
occasion after capturing up as a beta to
have a long conversation with him in
fact I am i sat with him for 54
consecutive hours after his capture he
was very upset as you can imagine he
cried a lot he said that he would never
know the touch of a woman he would never
know the joy of fatherhood and I said
listen you are not a victim here there
were 50,000 people in those towers what
did you think we were going to do did
you think we weren't going to try to
find you to capture you or to find her
or kill bin Laden and he said that he
never wanted to attack the United States
on September 11th he wanted to attack
Israel he said all he ever wanted to do
was to kill Jews and I said listen I am
the nicest guy that you're going to meet
in this experience
my colleagues are not as nice as I am so
if there's one thing that you do it's
that you should cooperate and he said
you seem like a nice man but you're the
enemy and I'll never cooperate
I said suit yourself later that night a
CI a private jet flew in three FBI
agents and I loaded him onto the plane
he asked me to hold his hand the whole
time and I wished him the best of luck
and I never saw him again well two
months later I returned to CIA
headquarters and on the strength of the
other Zubaydah capture I had been
promoted and I was named the Executive
Assistant to the CIA's deputy director
for operations and it was in that
capacity that I had access to literally
everything in the CIA every operation
every sensitive compartment everything
and it was in that position but I
realized that we had initiated this
torture program now I I was in the
cafeteria one day and a former colleague
from the CIA's Counterterrorism Center
approached me and said hey I'm glad I
ran into you um do you have any interest
in being and these were his words
certified in the use of enhanced
interrogation techniques I had never
heard the term before so I asked him
what it meant and he said very excitedly
we're going to start getting rough with
these guys and I said well what does
that mean and then he delineate ADIZ ten
torture techniques and I said well that
sounds like a torture program I said I
think I have a moral problem with that
and I declined well as it turned out of
the fourteen people that they approached
asking if they wanted to be trained in
these torture techniques I was the only
one who said no that was a source of
great disappointment for me but I kept
my mouth shut
I left the CIA two years later and still
be up to my mouth shut but then in late
I couldn't live with the
administration's lies anymore it seems
like every time I turned on the
television President Bush was denying
that there was a torture program and the
CIA's director at the time and and
directors after him George Tenet were
all denying that there was a torture
program and I knew that that was a lie I
knew that they were lying to the
American people and I believe in
transparency I believe that the American
people have a right to know what their
country is doing in their name and so I
decided in December of 2007 that I was
going to blow the whistle on this
program and I gave a nationally
televised interview to ABC News in which
I did exactly that I said three things
three things that have utterly changed
the course of the rest of my life I said
that the CIA was torturing its prisoners
I said that torture was official US
government policy it was not the result
of a rogue as President Bush had said
and I said that the torture program had
been personally approved by the
President himself as you can imagine
within 24 hours the FBI began
investigating me and this is where the
story in my view becomes very sad
it becomes unamerican the FBI
investigated me for a full year from
December 2007 to December 2008 and they
decided at the end of that investigation
that I had not committed a crime that
the interview was not a crime because
the information was not inherently
classified and so they closed the
investigation four weeks later Barack
Obama was inaugurated as president of
the United States Barack Obama the
self-described most transparent
president in history and I should prep
this by saying that I believed in the
whole hope and change slogan of the
Obama campaign not just that I worked on
the Obama campaign I took my children to
the inauguration so they can see this
historic moment when when for the first
time in history an african-american man
had become president I mean this was an
incredible moment for America but what I
did not know was that as soon as he
became president the CIA asked Barack
Obama to secretly reopen the case
against me which he did I had no idea
that I was under investigation I had no
idea that the FBI was intercepting my
phone calls and was reading my emails
and had teams of surveillance on me and
so I went about my regular business so
what was my regular business well
believe it or not John Kerry who at the
time was the chairman of the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee called me
and invited me to join the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee staff as the
chief investigator investigating waste
fraud abuse and illegality in the State
Department and so I took that job again
having no idea that I was under FBI
investigation for what became five
felony charges the FBI investigated me
for three more years and finally in
January of 2012 I was charged with these
five felonies including three counts of
espionage espionage is one of the
gravest crimes with which an American
can be charged and frequently it carries
with it the death penalty
for telling the American people that the
CIA was torturing its prisoners now
there's something that happened in the
interim and I had no idea the
significance of it until this whole
thing was over one of the great things
the most wonderful things about working
for the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee is that you get to have lunch
with foreign diplomats all the time and
you know you get together for lunch you
talk about the events of the day
whatever happens to be in the paper you
talk about diplomacy I got a call one
day a totally normal and routine call
from a Japanese diplomat it was the
number three in the Japanese Embassy in
Washington and he invited me to lunch so
we went to a small restaurant on Capitol
Hill and I remember the lunch as being
delightful
I remember we talked about Israeli
elections and Turkish elections and the
arab-israeli peace process and at the
end of the lunch he said to me so what's
next for you and I said well I'm
actually thinking of resigning from the
Senate Foreign Relations Committee I
promised senator Kerry that I would give
him two years it's been two and a half
and I think I'd like to go into business
for myself I have five kids I need to
start saving some money for college I
think I'd like to go into the private
sector and very excitedly he said no
don't do that if you give me information
I can give you money and I said what's
wrong with you do you have any idea how
many times I've made that pitch in my
career shame on you I told them I ended
the lunch and I went directly to the
office of the Senate security officer
and I said I was just pitched by a
foreign intelligence officer and he said
oh is it that damn Russian again and I
said no no it's it's a Japanese of all
things and he said really a Japanese
okay he said well sometimes they like to
see what we're doing these are the trade
and then he asked me to write it up as a
memo he was going to send it to the FBI
I said fine so I sat there in his office
and I wrote up the memo he sent it to
the FBI and then called me the next day
and said two FBI agents were going to
come and interview me so they finally
came up came to my office and said okay
here's what we want you to do we want
you to call him back and we want you to
try to get him to tell you exactly what
information he wants and how much money
he's willing to pay for it I said okay
if you want me to wear a wire or
something they said no we're going to be
at the next table and we'll just listen
to the conversation as at time so the
morning of that lunch they called me and
said that something had come up I should
just go forward with the lunch and write
them another memo so I met with this guy
a second time and then they asked me to
meet with him a third time and a fourth
time and a fifth time which I did
because I'm a patriot well I wrote up
these memos after each lunch and finally
in the fifth lunch he said that he had
been promoted he had been transferred to
his dream job and he was going to be the
number two in the Japanese embassy in
Cairo a year after that last lunch I was
arrested and we received discovery from
the Justice Department now discovery is
when the prosecution has to turn over to
the defense literally everything that
it's collected so that the defense can
use that to defend itself in this
discovery
we found a series of memos the first
indicated that there never was any
Japanese diplomat he was an FBI agent
undercover and he was trying to get me
to commit real espionage and I asked my
lead attorney why would they do such a
thing
and he said because they have a
case and they know it's a case I
hadn't committed espionage I had blown
the whistle fair and square I told the
American people what they had a right to
know well we also received three memos
between the CIA and the Justice
Department the CIA wrote to the Justice
Department and said charged him with
espionage the Justice Department wrote
back and said but he hasn't committed
espionage and the CIA wrote back and
said charge him anyway and make him
defend himself and that was the Obama
administration now the Espionage Act
here in the United States was written in
1917 to combat German saboteurs during
the first world war between 1917 and
2009 it was used to charge three
Americans with espionage for talking to
the press just under the Obama
administration eight Americans were
charged with espionage for speaking to
the press the Obama administration used
the Espionage Act as an iron fist to
stamp out dissent
now I was a guy who always colored
within the lines
I was nobody's special there there was
nothing unusual about me in any way I'm
just a guy I'm just a normal guy or one
of the things that so grossly
disappointed me with was that I was the
only one who said something you know
there were hundreds of people inside the
CIA who knew about this torture program
hundreds we now know from the Senate
torture report that people inside were
objecting to it they were writing cables
back from the secret prison saying this
is awful this is disgusting a couple of
them curtailed their assignments which
means they asked to return to
headquarters it's a career-ending move
but not a single one of them said
something publicly even worse than that
not a single one of them ever said
anything to the Senate or House
Intelligence Committee the oversight
committees I was the only one who did
that was a source of great
disappointment for me well in the end
Kim and I were talking about this off
camera a few minutes ago
in the end I had to defend myself
against these five felony charges I was
facing 45 years in prison and over the
course of 10 months our negotiations had
brought the Justice Department down to
10 years they wanted me to do 10 years
in a federal penitentiary this was what
they called their best and final offer
and I turned it down and I said two
things I said first of all I haven't
done anything wrong and because I
haven't done anything wrong I'm not
doing ten minutes let alone ten years in
prison
secondly I'm a very longtime former CIA
officer and in my 15 years in the CIA
I witnessed hideous crimes against
humanity war crimes and I'm going to
have to testify in my own defense and I
might accidentally say something about
these horrible crimes that I've
witnessed my colleagues perpetrate over
the years and it might slip out in the
course of my my testimony
and so the CIA came back and said
alright dude two and a half years you'll
end up serving under two I actually
turned that down and then one of my
eleven attorneys the one who I liked and
respected the most pulled me aside and
said you just don't get it
this isn't about innocence or guilt this
is about cutting your losses this is
about inflicting the least amount of
pain on yourself and your family it
doesn't matter whether you did it or
didn't do it the federal government wins
ninety eight point two percent of its
cases according to ProPublica and he
said if you were my brother I would beg
you to take this deal so I'm begging you
take the deal he said this can be a blip
in your life or it can be the defining
event of your life you could be home
early enough that your children won't
even remember you were gone or you can
get out when your children are in
college
and so I took the deal it becomes an
economic decision with that said I would
do the whole damn thing over again
somebody had to say something
transparency is real it's important a
democracy can't function without
transparency and again the American
people have a right to know what their
government is doing in their name and so
I'm glad that I said something I'm glad
that I said something I'm glad that I
have continued to say something it's
cost me my marriage my wife left three
months ago she said it's just too much
work to be mrs. John Kiriakou to tell
you the truth I don't blame her but I
had to do the right thing and this was
the price that that we all have to pay
it was all worth it thanks for listening
John this is an incredible story a
remarkable story
so really the FBI were involved in an
attempt to entrap you is that what you
were just telling us there yeah it's all
about him traffic to tell you the truth
and that's why when I got to prison I've
been in prison let's see March April
major four months when Ed Snowden went
public with his regulations and I wrote
an open letter to ed Snowden I found
loaded up with a private letter through
we have a mutual attorney but I told him
what I thought he should do just from
the benefit of my own experience I told
him to find the best national security
attorney's money could buy essentially
my insurance which he did he engaged my
attorneys I told him to cultivate his
natural bases of support especially on
Capitol Hill now that's taking a little
bit of time but he's done that as well
and it's funny because the far left of
the far right ends up meeting at a point
that the ideological spectrum I believe
is not a straight line it's a circle and
and they've come together at the point
where they really care about civil
liberties and it's those civil
libertarians on the left and the right
who have come out in support of it
Snowden because of that we are finally
just now beginning to see elements of
the Patriot Act fall by the wayside
finally after 16 years I think that's
thanks to Ed Snowden and the third thing
I said and this was the most important
thing don't ever ever under any
circumstances talk to the FBI I said
they will lie they will cheat they will
twist your words they'll wiretap you and
then take your statements out of context
to use against you in court
remember they get promoted if you go to
prison that's the only way for them to
get ahead in their
careers is for you to go to prison and
if you go to prison for a long period of
time they're going to get a performance
bonus they're going to get transferred
to a better position inside the FBI I
mean it's ridiculous it's like
everything a democracy should not be so
I got a visit from it from Ed's father
he actually came to prison to visit me
and told me that Edie had appreciated
the letter that he had taken it
seriously and that um and he was abiding
by it that meant a lot to me all worth
it huge um it's extremely important for
people who are going through this to
have people who have been through it
before
able to be like them so that was an
amazing initiative that you suck um
it'll work you on that point I got very
lucky actually um before I left for
prison there was something like 625
people who had expressed interest in
being placed on a mailing list and email
mailing list um just to receive
something from me
saying I'm fine I'm in prison it's not
so bad I'm going to be okay so I wrote
this open letter and I sent it to my
attorney
she sent it to the publisher
firedoglake.com which no longer exists
that was Jane Hampshire and Jane I had
no idea Jane was friendly with Arianna
Huffington and so my initial open letter
which I called a letter from Loreto
received a million hits
thanks to Arianna Huffington when I will
be open letter to ed Snowden again I
just expected it to go essentially to my
attorney
maybe to a handful a couple hundred
other people but eventually it would
make its way back to ed again with
Ariana's help it went viral I ended up
with over two million hits
CNN drove to the prison to interview me
the American news program 60 minutes
came to the prison it was in everything
from like Time magazine to playboy to
The Economist's to the Atlantic Monthly
and thanks to Arianna we got it
immediately back to egg 2 million hits
and and I got my side of the story out
there this is something that I learned
early on is we really need to take
advantage of our access to the media I
mean we can we can have these great
ideas and we can sit and talk amongst
ourselves about how smart we are and how
creative we are we create our ideas we
we have and it doesn't make any
difference if nobody knows that we're
doing it so if we have access to the
press that's how we win you know John
let me weigh in here first of all thank
you so much
what an incredible story you are a hero
for done what you did and I admire your
courage thank you so much you know in my
case the first priority was to make sure
that I don't get bail because they are
very much aware that the moment you are
outside you can tell your side of the
story and in my case they had told their
side of the story
with the indictment and a massive press
release and they gave my indictment and
some background information to about a
dozen news outlets who were ready to
press print the moment the rate went
down on my on my home and on my family
so for me to be able to get bail and to
get out and talk about what happened was
their biggest concern because they knew
already you know that what they did was
at the edge of what's possible in a
novel copyright case and then their
second priority was after I had bail to
silence me by disallowing me to have any
Internet access whatsoever anyone
coming to my house had to leave their
smartphones outside I had very strict
their conditions that were restricting
my speech and limiting my ability to be
out there and tell my story and
certainly they cease all my money to
make sure that I can't afford any
lawyers because that is the biggest
power they have they have unlimited
funds they have a huge war chest they
can keep going for years and appeal
everyone you have until you run out of
money you run out of patience with your
relationships who just can't carry the
burden of this fight anymore
that's why your relationship broke up
that's why my relationship broke up they
really want to destroy you and silence
you so for you to do the exact opposite
for you to go and write these letters
from prison and do all these interviews
and to keep talking about it that is
really the most powerful and courageous
thing and the more people learn about
your story the more people can hear what
happened to you they would get angry
they will feel just like I did listening
to you very upset you know not
understanding why a government could do
something like that why a government
that is supposed to serve the people is
doing something like that to their own
citizens and for that I want to applaud
you it's amazing that you tell us a
story and share it with everyone thank
you so much you raised such an important
point that that I meant to to mention
and the point is that it's not just to
prosecute you you're right it's to ruin
you financially personally
professionally is to separate you from
your friends from your family from your
natural allies or supporters
they do they do these things in the
United States there are two two
strategies that the prosecution uses in
the United States what is called charge
stacking and that is um let's say you
really did do something wrong let's say
you conspired with somebody to do
something well they won't just charge
you with conspiracy they'll charge you
with five and 20 different crimes and
they'll force you to defend yourself
against those 20 different crimes to the
point where you go bankrupt and that
usually takes you know six to twelve
months and then once you're bankrupt and
you're weak and you're desperate they'll
come back and they'll say well we'll
drop all of these charges but one if you
plead guilty to one and take this number
of years in prison well that's what they
intended in the very beginning they know
they knew you didn't commit these 20
crimes they intended for you to take the
plea and because you're broken by then
well of course you're going to take the
plea and that's why they win ninety
eight point two percent of their cases
now the other reason that you're going
to take that plea is that juries here in
the United States especially where you
and I have been charged in Eastern
District of Virginia because they would
convict a bologna sandwich of a crime if
the government asked them to you know
when your jury Kim and this is a warning
to you when your jury is made up of
people from the CIA the FBI the Homeland
Security Department the Defense
Department and the intelligence
contractor community you don't have a
printer you can't win it doesn't matter
if you're innocent you're not going to
win you're going to go to prison and if
you don't take a plea you're likely
going to die in prison that's their goal
their goal is for you to die in prison
not because they don't like you
necessarily but because they want to
scare the living daylights out of
everybody else
so that they can say you see what we did
to cure Iago you want that to happen to
you well you better keep your mouth shut
in the mean up that you're absolutely
right John and what I've learned about
the justice system in the US absolutely
confirms that let me give you one
example the judge that is on my case in
the district court in the Eastern
District of Virginia he was a lawyer
before he started his career as a judge
for Disney he was a partner in a law
firm for the world Tiffany corporation
their largest client and as anyone ever
heard of conflict of interest you know
he is the judge overseeing the world's
largest copyright case so that is number
one the second big surprise was how easy
they could commit judge shopping because
every judge in my district is on at a
certain date and if they make sure that
they submit their a case on that day
they know they're going to get that
judge so they picked my judge the judge
has a history to work on copyright for
the studios and on top of that I found
out through you know my research and we
hired an investigator that the judge
himself had an issue with the law
because someone burned his house down in
Virginia right and the fire department
came and the FBI came and was picking
the news and everyone was like who was
trying to hurt this judge and a big
investigation was jump-started and then
it turned out it was his own son and
they dropped the whole thing and never
did anyone hear about it again no one
was charged everything was dropped and
the judge was taken care of by his
government and this is the guy who made
a decision that said destroy all of
these servers worth why'd take down its
entire business that make 220 people
unemployed go do the raid you know how
in the world can you have a a fair
process with someone like that in charge
and you know everything that I've
learned over the last five and a half
years is that the entire system is
completely corrupt the ninety-eight
percent success rate that you spoke
about earlier those are not cases that
they win in court in front of the jury
those are all plea bargain deals they
torture you into accepting guilt even if
you've done nothing wrong they give you
this list of 20 charges in my case they
want me to throw in jail for 88 years
and you're absolutely right from
everything that I've seen from the
beginning in my case all they care about
is hurting me and killing me
they want to lock me up for as long as
possible and you are absolutely right
you know if I die they would probably
celebrate that you know and the thing is
every now and then they run into people
like us you know smart people who
understand what's going on who
understand that there are other people
out there who are interested in this who
are fighting against us in justice who
want to reform a system that is designed
to be unjust and you know our service to
the public really is to fight these
cases to the end to let everyone know on
and on again about what's going on
remind everyone because that is the only
way we're going to change anything about
this if you and I and Julian and all the
other people that are being persecuted
especially by this prosecution team in
the Eastern District of Virginia the
deep state persecutors they always
remind me of the church's Inquisition
you know if we don't do this no one else
will and you know we need to make sure
that through the events like this we let
people know about it and your story is
just a prime example because what you
have done you has exposed a crime it is
a crime in the United States to torture
someone
right yes it's a car and what do they do
to circumvent US law they ship them off
to foreign prison secret locations where
they torture them and then they say well
the US law really doesn't apply but then
in my copyright case they say just
because I have a few servers in the
United States and I've never been there
my business wasn't based there I didn't
sign up to their laws yet Here I am I
can be extradited so how does it work
that these guys can torture anyone they
want in these foreign sites by American
spies who do this or approve this
torture and then there's no charges for
them it simply because they say it's
happening outside of US borders and our
jurisdiction it's really a hypocrisy and
for someone like you who has exposed
such a significant crime which is
against American law international law
the you know human chart the the the
Human Rights Charter and you know
everywhere in the world country sign up
to treaties that something like this
should not happen and here you are you
point out the truth you tell the world
about these atrocities and terrible
crimes and as anyone other than you been
in jail for the US government torture
program no no the tortures are free the
men who came up with the torture program
are free the attorneys who justified it
are free the people who implemented it
are free even the CIA officers who
murdered prisoners during the course of
the interrogations are free I'm the only
one that was ever prosecuted and the
psychologists were the architects of the
program have just signed to catch Suman
to avoid going to trial for it to make
that worse that cash settlement is being
paid to the victims by the American
taxpayers because in two
and one the CIA indemnified the
psychologist and the CIA agreed to pay
all of their legal expenses and any
settlement that might come out of the
case and the middle readymade I think it
was reported something like forty six
million dollars 881 million dollars 81
million dollar one so that's the price
tag that was the price tag to design
something so sick and twisted yeah from
the small amount of information we know
from the Senate torture report which is
under severe lock and key and which the
agencies are doing absolutely everything
they can to never allow that full report
to be accessible accessed by the public
but from what little we do know in there
apparently they specifically recruited
CIA torturers who had a history of
domestic and sexual violence you know it
takes a special kind of monster to be
able to inflict that kind of physical
and psychological and emotional harm on
a person and not lose his soul you have
to have no soul in the first place
enable in order to be able to do
something like that I think a really
relevant question for New Zealanders
John in light of recent events and to
ask you is are you aware of New Zealand
or Australian troops and actresses
and/or special forces being involved in
extraordinary renditions the reason I
ask you this is because it has recently
come to light that they were and
initially we were told that though it
was revealed that they were involved in
handling detainees over to foreign
forces who they knew would torture them
just only a moment of caution here this
is very important John don't say
anything that could get you in legal
trouble again you need to be very
careful in answering these questions I
don't want you to say anything that is
going to get you an ego trouble yeah
yeah thank you can I appreciate that
problem very is fine and I definitely
don't have to get
a knowledge that you have there just in
theory the reason I ask is because
recently it has been revealed and the
famous investigative journalist Nicky
hoggers book - and run that New Zealand
forces have been involved in massacring
unarmed civilians in Afghanistan
including women and children and revenge
raids that were launched upon villages
that supposedly contain militants but it
turned out they didn't they killed them
all and burned all the houses down as
literally revenge rate and so I'm very
interested to know if you're aware owed
forces other than allied American forces
that allied to the Americans also being
involved an extraordinary rendition I'm
not to tell you the truth certainly I
never ever encountered a New Zealander
when I was in the region and even the
Australians when I was in Pakistan and
we captured an Australian national
Australians jumped up and down because
they wanted him to be turned over to
Australia immediately rather than to go
to Guantanamo
so no I'm glad to say I never
encountered any Australian or New
Zealand military officials intelligence
officials nobody involved in this kind
of thing that that's good snark quite
frankly considering everything else I've
been involved in yeah I actually hadn't
heard that about the villagers it's it's
all has it's true it's it's a it's a war
crime it is literally a war crime and
it's one that the New Zealand government
had gone to quite some lengths to try to
cover up landed there are calls for a
public inquiry into what happened and
the government is resisting those
holding the inquiry yeah yeah of course
and I've gone to some lengths as well to
attempt to discredit the authors of the
book even though they are an impeachable
as per their record and so we don't know
yet what will come of that that there
are certain
New Zealand code fighting very hard to
get the truth out there about what it's
happened and about our involvement in
this crime okay Kim do you have anything
else that you want to ask John I think
we'll go to Q&A shil because I know
there's been a number of questions asked
yes and I still have a couple of things
actually if it's wrong I really want to
pick your brains because you know you're
one of the guys who was inside for such
a long time
and you know your understanding of the
intelligence community is priceless
so if you don't mind I have a couple of
questions just like the dark sides right
that they used outside of US borders to
torture people they are also using the
five eyes partner countries like New
Zealand Australia the UK and Canada to
spy on Americans where the US themselves
legally is not permitted to do that and
then through xkeyscore and all these
other programs they get access to that
information anyway so they outsource the
spying to these other countries on
Americans and at the same time the u.s.
spy agencies give those foreign agencies
access to their own fiber network give
them access to all the backdoors all the
tools that they have developed and then
through the backdoor
they are spying n mass on Americans
which is a breach of the Constitution
and US law it's that kind of a good
description of what went on to
circumvent any kind of prosecution in
torture cases is this how spy agencies
what you would say in your experience
operate if they have a challenge
nationally and it's against the law then
they will utilize friendly nations and
their agencies to still do it and
circumvent the law absolutely yes
this is the nature of our spy agencies
here the CIA
the CIA's culture is such that it will
push the bounds of legality until is
slapped down and told to stop we've gone
through these periods in modern American
history where we have had strong
oversight committees for example 1975 to
1981 where we had Frank Church chairing
the the first Senate Intelligence
Committee and Otis Pike chairing the
House Intelligence Committee those were
strong overseers and then during the
Reagan administration we had weak
overseers well frankly since September
11th I wouldn't even say that the that
the intelligence committees our
oversight committees I would say that
their cheerleading committees precisely
because they just cheer on anything the
CIA proposes to do and in many cases the
CIA doesn't even bother to inform the
committee's what it's doing the
committees have to find these things out
from the press and so the short answer
to your question chemist's is yes that's
exactly what they're doing
they're using any means at their
disposal to spy on American citizens and
to allow foreign intelligence services
to spy on American citizens on their own
behalf I agree with you that it is
illegal it's unconstitutional it's
illegal it's unethical in fact it's even
a violation of the NSA Charter which
specifically says that NSA is forbidden
under any circumstances to spy on
American citizens but it happens every
single day in post 9/11 America yeah so
with this serial law breaking going on
and a new president in the White House
why don't you think that Trump is doing
something about this why don't you think
that you know anyone new in charge this
new government isn't going in and saying
hey wow we are doing all these things
and this is all unlawful how come no one
is cracking down on the stuff you know I
never believed in the idea the notion of
of a deep state well then let me correct
that sure there's a deep state sure but
I never believed in the notion that it
controls the modes of government until
now yeah you know and now I mean it's
like not even deep anymore it's it's out
of it it's the open deep stage when you
say I want to see it's exactly right
it's like they're not even they're not
even afraid to be identified as the deep
state any and they don't even have to
make an effort anymore because the media
is so involved it's what they're all
lemmings there are some things and they
go right off the cliff with the with the
lead lemming I you know I'm going to
preface these comments by saying I think
I think Donald Trump is a madman I think
he's he's unfit mentally emotionally and
intellectually to be President I think
this is one of the his election is one
of the greatest mistakes that Americans
have made in modern times with that said
he believes that there's a deep state
and he believes that they're out to get
him in addition to being out there to
get other other people well they're
showing the whole world that they ought
to get him I mean what's going on with
with the mass leaking with the liberal
news media attacking him I mean I get
what you're saying about him but he is
one important thing that I think has
happened in the United States you know
more and more people are becoming aware
of how they are constantly being lied to
they're becoming aware of government
abuse they're becoming aware that they
are really just being used that they are
not electing politicians to serve them
but politicians only serve their own
interests and
interests of their rich donors so in
Donald Trump
I believe Americans have seen an
outsider who is not part of that
establishment who even amongst other
rich people is not really welcome
because of his attitude and his ego and
his I'm doing it my way
attitude right so in a way this election
was I would say the desperate effort by
people you know who see what's going on
to have someone completely outside of
the political establishment to come in
and to change something see one on drain
the swamp he want one unlock her up you
know people want to have a president in
the White House even a character like
Trump who is going to go in and change
all of this stuff you know and it's so
frustrating to see how easily the deep
state is just manipulating everything
and I am pretty sure if Trump doesn't
get old
if he doesn't expose the crimes that
have been done by the deep state under
Obama the mass surveillance the breaches
of the Constitution's the breaches mass
breaches of law if he doesn't drain the
swamp as he said it will be gone gone
before the end of the year everything is
building up to an event where he is
being removed as a president of the
United States and the longer he is
inactive his inaction is going to get
people to agree with that and not you
know be part of of the group that is
going to fight against his removal so I
think you know it's it's a great
opportunity for the u.s. to have a
change agent even a person like Trump
who
I agree with you has an enormous ego you
know does does things in a way that you
know you and I wouldn't do but at the
same time he is a victim to the deep
stage just like us
he is definitely right now a victim and
his opportunity is to go in there find
out everything that they've done expose
it and use this law breaking to reform
the intelligence community in the deep
state and expose what Obama and his
people have done to undermine the rights
of their citizens because that in itself
I think it's the most powerful heroic
thing that he could do no one would care
any more about his ego and about you
know how important it is for him to have
won this election for him to be
president if he did that you know we
could have a reset we could have a
restart of all of these institutions to
be serving the American citizens without
undermining the laws and undermining
their rights and frankly taking their
rights away more and more you know don't
you agree that that Trump could be that
a change agents simply because of him
not being part of this establishment yet
I actually do agree with that um the the
problem I think is that he has he has
become so deeply mired in domestic
problems of his own making witness this
white supremacy insanity that we're
going through right now then it might be
a problem
but but yeah I think you're exactly
right see this is the problem this is
the problem with my friends on the Left
I I'm a third generation Democrat until
my arrest that I left the Democratic
Party over this and I lifelong
progressive Barack Obama should have
been a legendary hero for all of us and
instead Barack Obama was the one into
we are right now civil rights are civil
liberties in many cases are human rights
and so you're right Kim that at least on
the international stage Donald Trump can
rehabilitate himself by by giving us
back our rights and standing up to the
deep state that Obama nurtured and yes
yes I believe that and you know that as
good as that is sorry go ahead miss me
I'm interested to know how did it happen
that Bush who instituted the torture
program that your case was dropped under
Bush you see ya nothing was brought that
was reopened under mister hope and
change Obama does this mean that Obama
was just a figurehead how is it the
bomber mister hope and change became the
persecutor grand persecutor of
whistleblower well I think that it's
actually darker than the idea of Obama
being a figurehead I mean I'll give you
two different answers one is a quick one
there was a book that was published in
2013 called a double down by Mark
Halperin and John Holliman two noted
political commentators and in this book
President Obama sat for an interview and
he said two things that were really
chilling to me um one very
matter-of-factly he said in response to
a question I never said I was a liberal
it's as though we were tricked into
thinking that he was progressive the
other thing he was talking about the
drone program and he said I never had
any idea that I would be so good at
killing people well that's that's not
something to brag about or to marvel
over I mean look at look at george w
bush's last month as president and in
george w bush's last month as president
he took actions that resulted in the
deaths of two people with the use of the
drone in brock obama's last month as
president he killed 424 people with
drones but how is that liberal how is
that progressive the other thing is
and we've seen this through modern
history in the in the states with
inexperienced presidents the CIA loves
an inexperienced president social
engineering done because I can socially
anything to do what they want that's
exactly it it's social engineering they
know that they can mold this guy into
their own image and so here you have a
president who has just been elected with
literally zero national security
experience he's elected but not yet
inaugurated and so they bring him into
the fold they give him access to the the
most closely held secrets they show him
the the blue border reports the black
border reports that are five and six
levels above top secret and they say mr.
president-elect we want to tell you all
the cool things were doing overseas well
then they have him they've recruited him
they've made him one of the guys he's in
the club now and once he's in the club
he'll do anything they want
yeah well Trump's not in the club he'll
they don't want him in the club and they
don't want yet because he's in the deep
state wanted to get Hillary to win more
than anything because they know with her
it would have been the next four years
the next eight years just like under
Obama she is correctly complicit in all
of it they don't have to worry that any
of their legalities are ever going to
come to light it's just going to cover
it up because she's part of this illegal
conspiracy that they have going and
Trump it's nothing more than a risk to
them they they don't like him they want
him gone and I don't think Trump is
someone who can be socially engineered
yeah you know they prefer keeping him in
the dark and and telling him almost
nothing because they are worried that if
he understands what really happened in
the United States under Obama that he is
going to stop that that he's going to
we'll expose that and say guys what are
you doing
you know the people didn't sign up for
that they didn't vote us in so you can
do this stuff and that's what they're
worried about and let me give you a very
big example of that just before Obama
less left office I don't know if you
probably read that in the news the NSA
went to the FISA Court and the White
House and the NSA admitted that they
have been spying on Americans and they
didn't really provide any detail on how
many and they as I usually do make it
sound like incidental and accidental but
they basically admitted that they acted
unlawfully spying on Americans and then
on the next page they're saying but now
that we know that we did that we deleted
everything we just went into our
databases found everything that we
captured that we shouldn't have and we
deleted it and what did they delete
Hillary Clinton's emails from her
private email server and everything else
that has happened in the Obama
administration that could come and haunt
them because these emails as you well
know as you know an expert in the
intelligence community were hoovered up
by the NSA spy systems automatically you
know doesn't even require an agent to do
it Todd by targeting her that happened
automatically because it was a private
server it was not a state email system
so they Hoover it all up they have it in
the Utah spy cloud and then they went to
FISA just before Obama is gone to get
permission or basically to tell the FISA
Court
we've now deleted all the stuff that
we're not supposed to have that's how
they cover things up I mean it's
incredible how how openly they do it you
know and
understands how they work when you read
the stuff you just go up widen the FISA
Court say hey hold on a minute preserve
this as evidence if you say you did this
unlawfully but someone needs to
investigate it someone needs to look at
it but you have these FISA Court judges
that really just rubber-stamp everything
that I see puts to them and they are not
interested in any kind of investigation
because it makes themselves look that
sure law but someone like Trump could
appoint a special prosecutor to look in
into the math Constitution breaches of
the spy agencies he could you know have
sessions through that in a heartbeat
that's what they are worried about and
what they are doing right now is try and
get as rid of as much of the evidence as
they can because you know if they fail
in the Coweta of Donald Trump they can't
remove them you know they are risking
that they will be seriously exposed
because I believe that Donald Trump
would be taking action if he had a full
picture of what really went on during
the Obama years I would agree with that
I think he does not have a full picture
you know another thing to think of too
it is the CIA the NSA all the
intelligence agencies are our civil
service agencies people are there for 20
25 30 35 years at a time
and so the leaders inside the CIA with
the exception of the director himself
everybody else from the Deputy Director
level all the way down came of age in
the Obama administration they're all
Obama holdovers this is very much Barack
Obama's CIA that's exactly right
and there are so many Obama loyalists
still there and they know what they have
done they know
as ever there was a real investigation
into their activities they would all go
to jail or they should arrange it
without ever they are in cover-up mode
and they are trying still now to prevent
this president because they are scared
of him I think that's exactly right yeah
and you can say whatever you want about
Trump that is a quality that he has and
a potential that he has where I just
haven't joined the group of people that
said our Trump is horrible and this and
that because he as crazy as it is is our
best hope to get something changed
because he's on our side he himself is
exposed to this dirt it's true it's true
and it is pointing because they have so
bottled him up politically and again a
lot of this is of his own making because
he does not have Washington experience
but they have so bottled him up
politically that he's focused now solely
on saving himself and his agenda and on
domestic issues when was the last time
Donald Trump said anything about mass
surveillance I can't even remember yeah
well I mean the only person who said
something about it is Sean Hannity Sean
Hannity on Fox he talks about the deep
state all the time and it's a it's
Trump's favorite programs I'm pretty
sure it is much more aware about the
issues now than he was when he got
elected and you know if I was from and I
put myself into his shoes right and I
have all these leaks coming out hundreds
hundreds of leagues my transcripts of
phone calls with foreign leaders and
then the intelligence community which
has only one purpose is to protect my
information can find and produce a
single leader
and stop the leaking I mean how dumb do
you have to be not to understand that
it's them who is doing it you know it's
them was doing it no one is going to be
found out and it's because they don't
like this president they want to get rid
of Trump at all costs and you know to me
personally I think there is an
opportunity here you know if this
president understands that his enemy is
also our enemy and it's also the enemy
of the American people and the American
dream and the future of America once he
understands that I am think and I'm
thinking is on the way to getting that
you know there is a real opportunity to
change this thing I think that is a
brilliant Abed everything that you just
said through and important and it's
something that the American people are
simply not focused on yeah you're right
this the deep state the intelligence
apparatus the intelligence and the
federal law enforcement APRA's are the
enemies of the American people and the
American dream
yeah and you know the good thing is even
within those dire times where all these
crimes are being committed there are
people like you with a moral compass you
know who think ethics are something to
cherish who will work with WikiLeaks
with the media to put these stories out
there and if there's one friend that is
really encouraging then it is the amount
of people that are coming forward with
information you know it is increasing
Snowden has opened the floodgates and
now everyone who is aware of these
criminal acts
you know has to ask ask themselves their
own conscience you know if there's
something I want to continue doing or do
I want to join forces with people like
John with people like ad with the CIA
whistleblower who's giving WikiLeaks all
the stuff the world 7 stuff the media
ops that are coming out everything that
is coming out right these people right
now have an opportunity to reform what's
happening in the deep state they have an
opportunity to release as much as they
can so that the president has a chance
to point the finger at it and to change
this because if we don't take this
opportunity now if it doesn't happen now
I don't think we will get another
opportunity there's now a global arms
race in the intelligence world every
country wants to have the kind of powers
that the US has it's going to be used
more and more radically to to cut down
on the sand to silence people that are
not in the interest of a particular
government and you know now it's the
time we really have to do something with
urgency here and as crazy as it sounds
trump is probably the best guy to do it
I'm going to press the dissenting
opinion here I am and so I think that
you're serious brilliant eyes I think
you that you're correct that probably
the only way out of the hole that he's
in right now would be for Trump himself
to blow the whistle and for him to blow
the whistle on the Obama government on
the pay-to-play of the Clinton
Foundation and Dyke Clinton and Dyke
debbie Wasserman Schultz offense and
that's what promised Americans and if he
doesn't do it if he doesn't do it in the
end price one Pietschmann are coming it
will come before the end of this year if
he doesn't do it you'll be gone no one
would tear about fighting for him if he
doesn't deliver on those promises I
think
is brilliant and I genuinely hope that
he takes that advice that he has the
strength and integrity to take that
advice however I go to doubt first is
that he is so completely surrounded by
generals and that he's surrounded by
generals who are complicit and a lot of
what has happened particularly in the
Wars of the last 15 years and I think
the reason he's being surrounded by
those generals is for him to be taken
into the fold that's like Plan B plan
one is get rid of them you know plan 2
is try to get them still on to their
side so that's the first thing that I
would say the second thing is I think
that this is not just a list right war
or an a deep state versus the people war
it's a class war and when you look at
the photos of Hillary Clinton and of
Trump together of which there are many
while he may not be an insider he
certainly walked in those circles for
long enough and there is a difference
between the haves and have-nots in that
sense and he will side with his class
against the majority of the people so
what I see is that it's more like
competing mafia clans it's like the
Clemson clan is like a mafia and Trump
crowd is like a mafia and they're
fighting it out and having them mafia
war together within government I also
see that Trump is in charge of the
police state here's one of the police
unions and agencies and everything
rooting for him and in Clinton silica
she was pushing TPP PPP was signed on to
by all the heads of the intelligence
agencies they all wanted it to pass
so Trump coming in and ditching the TPP
basically on day one would have put him
on their list as well from that
point so what we have now is the police
state versus the intelligence agency and
while Trump is leading the police state
Trump will never be for the people who
are on the ground because there is a
fleet state who enforce the mechanisms
of control above and over the people who
are on the ground so we have this weird
conflict is created like the bipolar and
society alone you see at the moment
we're actually to be honest with you
neither side is great the police
agencies have massive
problems and corruption racism systemic
corruption systemic issues oppression of
people and of activists and then the
intelligence agencies are just like next
level worst of all like the stuff that
they've been involved in from war crime
so it sort of transitions to torture to
everything else they are the worst of
the worst so now we have like would you
like to support the system of domestic
oppression or would you like to support
the system of international oppression
and that's the choice that's being sold
to people I also say that I'm completely
disgusted with liberals I come from an
activist background I'm still an
activist to this day I find it
incredible that there are activists out
there who have been targeted by the
intelligence agencies and the movements
have been targeted by the intelligence
agencies for the last six years and
decades before that they have been
personally targeted and oppressed by
Obama's administration and by Hillary
Clinton who are now saying oh the CIA is
not that bad all the intelligence
agencies at MIT and actually you know
they're trying to do a good thing giving
road trunks yeah I think we'll match
with them everything's fine you have
people like at Thunder on Twitter who
literally says I am the leader of the
resistance
he is the funder for Hillary Clinton
literally the funder for the Democratic
Party and he claims to be an activist
leading the resistance his party has
just spent the last six years open and
activist targeting and undermining and
destroying the lives of activists that
they now claim to be marching with the
games Trump so it is a complete and
utter class and anybody who will get in
bed with Hillary Clinton and her
financial backers and the intelligence
agencies and then call themselves an
activist needs a wake-up call if you are
going to be an activist at least be on
principles that if you are marching
alongside Hillary Clinton and her
cronies you are nothing better people
scrap for the Clinton mafia so that's my
two cents and on the other side as you
are marching with the National Front and
David Duke well don't be surprised that
people are calling you a Nazi or
races because you've got no business
matching with those people and calling
yourself an activist either and I'm sure
I will lose a lot of friends by pointing
this out but what I'm saying is that
both sides are corrupt oh oh isn't it
what Trump said it's like a profit
neither side has the moral high ground
at all yeah I am aware that there are
very legitimate activist organization
who are smart enough to not have fallen
for the lease versus right / cirhonk o
Clinton versus Trump the intelligence
agencies versus police agencies that is
the anti-war movement that is the
legitimate legitimate peace protestors
these are not side with either the left
or the right and they are genuinely
working for peace for the planet they
want to shut down menu they want to shut
down the torture they want to shut down
extraordinary rendition they're fighting
to shut down the drone program and you
don't hear those people going yeah let's
go punch a Nazi and you don't hear them
going well it's you know kill the
Liberals they're not starting militias
they are genuinely involved in a
movement for peace those are the same
people those are the people who we need
to support world beyond worg go and
check them out these are the real
activists activists who are not aligned
with either side these are the people
who wishes support so that's my two
cents on that now just to switch topics
on you really quickly and John I want to
just talk about quickly sanctioned
League versus unsanctioned leagues
because it seems to me that people like
you get in a lot of trouble for telling
the truth but then we have people like
well Bob Woodward was specifically who I
wanted to talk about Bob Woodward is a
very very famous political author and he
has written books about a series of
American presidents and I'm just quickly
going to share my screen and show you
something that I have here on Twitter as
for much as this year it's a quote from
Bob Woodward
quotas I have had presidents in
Republican and Democrat administrations
provide information that is technically
classified Billy is talking to Bill
O'Reilly bill you know that happens all
of the time and that's Bob Woodward now
Bob Woodward wrote on the books about
what super books that Bush's was and
also book about Obama when I read those
books I couldn't do the few things in
them that I literally had my mouth
hanging open I actually sent these to
Glenn Greenwald a few quotes a few years
back and a few other people because they
really shocked me so the first thing
that really shocked me is that the names
of the program CIA program names of
systems details of technical systems
that and the framework by which military
operations are conducted in Afghanistan
you can find these and they put you can
find each operation detail you can find
very specific testimony from and from
even named people and unnamed sources
about things that are happening inside
the agency and these book sell millions
of copies and end up on the New York
Times bestseller list and also as he
said himself he's received class
technically classified information from
presidents on both sides but then there
was also a story in there that really
shocked me those two stories that really
shocked me one was they were talking
about how the CIA wanted to get an
Afghan warlord onto their side so they
women offered him a cash prizes however
much money and the warlord said no thank
you I don't want to accept the money and
so the CIA said well what should we do
about that I know we'll tear up the
fifty thousand pound bomb outside his
compound and then we'll go back to him
the next day and offer him less money so
they dropped a 50,000 pound bomb outside
his compound which I mean you might have
some idea of how much it cost to buy a
50,000 pound bomb I have no idea I just
think it's morally instable that they
would do such things sure enough they
went back to them afterwards and offered
him half the cash he accepted the deal
so this is the kind of thing that it
seems to be going on within these
agencies and that they think
okay for them to expend munition push
some public dollars to scare the
out of people so that they will take
exactly bribe money the second story
from Bob Woodward's book which I found
absolutely unbelievable was a story in
Iraq and believers from Iran the Kurdish
border and they were saying they were
talking about how they had a CIA asset
inside the building that compound where
these bad guys were and the CIA s it was
reporting to giving them information
from within and so they went to blow up
the compound that they see to themselves
well we did not tell our asset that
we're going to blow up the compound that
using in cases you know it exposed us
somehow so we'll just blow it up with
him in it and that's what they did they
looted the place and killed their an
asset and I could not believe there was
they would write about this suitable
that they'd do it second of all that
they would write about it in a Bob
Woodward New York Times bestseller so
I'd like to know what is what do you
have to say about this that the
manifestation of these like horrific war
stories and this highly classified
information in books that sells millions
of copies and make millions of dollars
whereas you told the world that war
crimes being committed and you end up in
jail why is Bob Woodward not in jail
[Music]
you're due to John
John you're on mute alright I'm amused
that you're surprised by any of this
the CIA has been doing these kinds of
things since its creation in 1947 let me
tell you a short anecdote - after the
episode ADA capture I told you I was
promoted and named executive assistant
to the deputy director I had a lovely
private office with brand-new expensive
furniture and I was enjoying my office
and sitting there like this one day and
I happened to be turned and looking past
the secretary into the hallway I had a
direct line of sight into the hallway
and as I'm sitting there like this
looking Bob Woodward walks past the door
without a security expert sorry a
security escort and I said to the
secretary was that Bob Woodward that
just walked past the door from the
Washington Post and she said yeah I said
what in the world is Bob Woodward doing
walking the halls and she said oh you
didn't see the memo the director gave
him free access and we're all ordered to
cooperate with him and I thought man so
that's how the game is played when you
want to get the official story out there
you can leak to your heart's content
because it makes the CIA look good it
makes the White House look good and it
makes the Pentagon look good and that's
what they want at the same time the
White House and its employees are the
most prolific leakers in all of
government
they leak for a variety of reasons they
lead to make the president look good
they lead to make him look strong they
leak to to create trial balloons just to
see what the public reaction would be to
something to some policy changer or or
nomination that they're considering we
also need to remember that there's a
difference between leaking and
whistleblowing whistleblowing is
bringing to light any evidence of waste
fraud abuse
legality or threats to the public health
or public safety leaking is leaking and
people leak for a variety of reasons
they leak to make themselves seem
important
they leak to to help to quench this this
need for for the thrill of leaking or a
thrill of being in contact with a
reporter sometimes they'll leak for
revenge maybe they don't like a
president or a boss or they've been
passed over for promotion and they'll
the leak just to get revenge on whoever
it is they believe wronged them but
that's not whistle blown it's the
whistle blowers that the administration
is afraid of because it's the list of
lowers who are the truth tellers that's
what they're worried about they don't
want the American people to know the
truth about these programs because these
programs most of them are patently
illegal and in many cases or even
violations of international law that's
what they're afraid of so yeah you know
I read all those books too I've read
every book that Bob Woodward's written I
read Jane Mayer's brilliant books and
they are chock full of classified
information those books would fall apart
if they didn't have classified
information but that's classified
information that has come as a result of
official leaks sanctions absolutely
right so you talk about the media being
important for us to raise but so often
they work in concert to promote war yen
and to suppress dissent so to what
extent were the rank-and-file CIA
personnel aware of the agency having
infiltrated the news media as women
we've heard about us we you know from
Mockingbird onwards the dictators heard
about this there's been a variety shows
and releases on WikiLeaks about the
topic so this is known with an agency
that the CIA has media cutouts and how
does what is the information flow from
from the agency to media channel well a
lot of that is actually classified a
probably shouldn't get into specifics
but you know operation Mockingbird
really did end at least at least and it
was targeting American journalists but
as you might imagine a journalist
foreign journalists all around the world
are targeted that's that's just the
nature of intelligence and the nature of
journalism it's not specific to the CIA
every Intelligence Service does that
kind of thing because that's how you
control the debate it's just a natural
thing to do
so yeah sure I mean every CIA officer
knows the history of operation
Mockingbird every CIA officer knows that
somewhere in the world journalists are
on the CIA payroll placing stories that
the CIA wants to be placed that's that's
just intelligence that's the way it is
or gotu kola the CIA invests into a an
entrepreneur six hundred million dollars
and then has that entrepreneur by The
Washington Post and directly influence
what the Washington Post is talking
about I mean the Washington Post has
become such a cover-up organization for
all of these crimes
you might recall recently some emails
were published where you know things
came out about the Hillary campaign and
and stuff and then the reporters would
write to Hillary to the to the people in
her campaign and say we're really sorry
that we have to ask her stuff kind of
you know bowing bowing down and and
saying you know we don't like we
probably have to ask some questions and
that's the culture today you know that
these large media organizations they are
all run by money and in times were
advertising income evaporates and they
don't really do as well as they did
before the internet you know they are
trying to find ways to survive and part
of survival is to partner with companies
with you know powerful people that will
keep them afloat and when Trump says the
failing almost broke New York Times it's
absolutely right you know they don't
even know how they're going to have
enough money next year to pay all that
stuff so you know they're working with
with people that have a certain agenda
and they feed them and keep them alive
and a lot of that I believe is going to
come out and future WikiLeaks releases
called new yards and it's also showing
how deeply the CIA and other agencies
have infiltrated the news media and not
just that you know it's one has to
wonder how does the CIA and then it's a
half all these backdoors they don't have
them into our technologies and our
devices because they sit like a hacker
would at home and and they try and find
the backdoors they try and find the
vulnerabilities in the software they
plant it themselves that is the way
they're doing it now they have their own
people within Microsoft with an apple
within Google
you know implementing into the source
code often without the knowledge of
these corporations implementing back
doors that allow these spy agencies
later to turn these devices into open
mics into open cameras and that's the
scary stuff the spy agencies went from
well how can we take advantage of what's
out there and make it work for us too
let's make it work for us let's put our
own people in there and let's manipulate
everything and this is the word we're
living in if you read a new story on the
New York Times of Washington Post
you have to ask yourself
someone you know who is part of the
media ops program of the deep state when
you when you install your Windows
software or you boot up your iPhone you
have to wonder how many people does
actually take to have a backdoor to turn
my phone into an open mic it's really
just one person one lead developer who
puts a piece of code into this enormous
universe of code that will give me
another backdoor and they planned
hundreds of those and by doing it they
are not only undermining our trust in
the media and into these technology
companies but they are giving the enemy
a powerful tool to strike against us
because these vulnerabilities that have
been created they leak somehow like the
entire NSA hacking toolkit that was
leaked not too long ago and now the
enemy has that organized crime has that
you know countries that are not friends
of the u.s. at all has access to that
and now they can use it to harm American
citizens and this is you know if Trump
would understand that the significance
the magnitude of how they are weakening
the security structure of the United
States by doing this stuff if he would
understand that I think he is the one
guy we can hope will do something about
it
you know but that's what's going on I
mean that is how everything is being
manipulated now and I know that with
first-hand experience from my case and
discovery that we had and the research
that I've done and I have a data
security background so I understand very
well how they are doing it and you know
it is very important that more and more
people come forward and release their
programs if you follow the vault seven
releases you know every week or two
Julian let's another document come out
you know it's incredible the amount of
backdoors that they have now into our
daily eyes every internet router is you
know an open door to them every
operating system no matter if it's
Windows Linux or you know Macintosh
every mobile phone from every
manufacturer no matter what operating
system they use it's ridiculous who gave
them the right to do that
you know nobody signed up for that if
the American people you know what would
really understand what's going on and
we're asked if they if they accept that
if they agree with that they would say
no if they were asked to vote in a
president who's going to turn that
off they would vote for him right that's
exactly right and as crazy as this may
sound Trump might be our best hope you
know but here's the there in reality
okay I mean they're really just three
options number one he becomes an ally
and he works with them and he allows
them to social engineer him into
compliance like they have done with
Obama and every president after Kennedy
okay that's number one number two he's
going to war there will be some bigger
news event that is just going to quiet
down everything else they will try and
get him engaged in some kind of war this
whole bombing of the Syrian airfield
which dominated the news for a week that
was really just give me a breather I
need some space you know and the third
option and that is you know the Kennedy
option if they can't make it work with
him and force him into compliance you
know they were either kill him or you
know it's impeachment doesn't work
they would they will get rid of him you
know so if I was from my best option
would be to really expose what is
happening here to bring all these crimes
to light and to shut these things down
and reform those agencies and he will
become a hero for generations and all
the young people that are following all
the stuff that are fed up with fake news
that know what's going on you know he's
going to become the hero no matter left
or right you know he can do what's right
the right thing and that is the
opportunity and that's why I supported
him because I saw just like brexit
that's not what the establishment wants
the establishment wanted to stay in the
European Union the establishment didn't
want Trump to win they don't want these
forces that interfere with their
globalist agenda and you know the plans
that they have so that's why I supported
him because he is a punishment for those
who have done this to the world for the
last few decades you know my only
disappointment with him in that respect
though was his appointment of Michael
Pompeo as the CIA director because Tom
Hale is completely these are completely
establishment manis he's a West Point
graduate he was a Republican and
conservative Republican congressman from
Kansas he was on the House Intelligence
Committee we're not going to get any
outside the box thinking from the likes
of Mike Pompeo and then to make matters
worse when Pompeo became director rather
than pulling his deputy director from
let's say the Republican staff on the
committee he named Gina Haskell the
CIA's deputy director Gina Haskell who
was one of the original creators of the
CIA's torture program so that was a
disappointment to me because he could
have made a bold
nomination which would have really been
a very important statement to the
establishment any digit but you know
what the problem is he doesn't know he
doesn't understand what's going on he
doesn't know what you know I know or to
you know yeah
value it in the news and then he gets
you know a certain percentage of it but
he doesn't really understand it I mean
his age it's he is not an Internet guy
he is not a technology guy you know his
mind is it's not structured to
understand these things unless someone
who he can trust to understand these
things can talk to him and explain it to
him and point him at evidence and show
him what's really happening that is the
biggest problem but you know there are
people out there there are voices out
there that she listens to that are
pointing these things out to him and
that's where the opportunity is because
if he gets it that's what I believe
if he gets what's going on he will want
to do something about it he will not be
complicit in this type of stuff mm-hmm
that is my that is my personal belief
and I know you know a lot of people
might disagree but when I saw a Trump
you know having a chance to become the
president and how the establishment had
an allergic reaction to him I knew that
he could be the guy you know he could be
the guy to to blow this all open and to
reform it all and it's a it's a huge
opportunity for him to make history
you know because what's happening right
now in the United States is not in the
service of the American people this is
all about money about economic control
you know this is not about our rights or
freedoms is not about making America
great again or the American dream it's
all about selfish commercial agendas
you know and the people are being used
and their rights are being trampled on
and the laws being broken on a daily
serial basis and that needs to stop and
I will not stop if people like you and I
and Julian and Edward and all the other
tools tell us out there are putting it
out there for everyone to understand and
you know what the people who get it our
numbers are growing you can see it in
the voting behavior already you can see
it you know people get it they want
change Obama got voted in for change and
hope and then disappointed everyone if
Trump does it again the next time
someone a complete outsider neither with
the Democrats or the Republicans is
going to get a boost there will be
someone coming out of midfield out of
nowhere where people will make an
investment of faith and trust and get
that guy in simply because they are fed
up with the lies and what the crimes the
government is committing at their
expense you know so it's just a matter
of time as long as we keep talking and
we're building this momentum and whether
we are organizing and we're talking
about it you know sooner or later this
whole thing is going to fall apart and
that is the biggest fear you know that's
why they fear you that's why they wanted
to put you in skit in jail for a decade
because you know people like you can
change the whole game for them they
understand that there's a couple of
things I just wanted and say one is this
a really good call about Gina Halperin I
might be mispronouncing her name she's
also associated with the Saudis and when
we saw a Trump go straight to Saudi
Arabia and touched the orb and do the
sword dance and the whole rigmarole and
that that told us a lot
you know the whole christening of the
Saudi and you terrorists into and of
course the Saudis are behind a lot of
terrorism in the world so he definitely
has people around him who are trying to
subvert him for the establishment
interest also we cannot ignore that bit
feasible so bit eases off again I might
be mispronounced
your name and the sister of Eric current
suit is also at Trump's table
Eric Prince is owned black water and
which has had a few name changes since
then he is the king of mercenary armies
and all of the war zones across the
world and also attempting to make money
on the militarization of the domestic
police forces in America so once again I
am with you Kim that I would love Trump
to be the one be the neo you know to
like blow it all up and get the truth
out there and change the system that the
people who are around him are the same
toxic militarists that have been
involved in previous administration yeah
I might be completely wrong
and completely naive about it but you
know when I see an opportunity you know
when I see even a 10% chance that by
them cornering him and alienating him
and putting him in a situation where
it's you know his downfall or theirs
that he might do the right thing that he
might understand how he can escape this
and how he can put them on on the spot
you know and if he does that he might
actually survive all of this deep state
collusion to get him out and if he does
you know he might actually become a hero
who knows I mean Trump is definitely
someone who would love to be everybody's
hero he loves to be loved okay so if you
watch this Donald and you want to be
loved
cut this crime down you know drain the
swamp do what you promised everyone
that's what we want what the whole world
is waiting for that is what we hope for
when Obama told us about the change you
know this is your opportunity don't be
like everyone else don't be a loser of
the deep state you know do your own
thing and be your own them and beat them
down with us with our hell right right
let's go I
right I hate them there's absolutely no
doubt about that they have used the
entire mass media to try to make event
al Tatum as well so he's definitely a
victim in that sense and being
persecuted by them in that sense they do
say the truth will set you free
hopefully he will find it within himself
to tell the truth
on an epic never before seen scale I do
hope that and actually them has only
real safety mechanism would be the
support of the public okay I just want
to address a concern I have really
quickly about some of the clips that I
see one more thing one more things to
learn the first step that I would take
if I was going to Trump was two would be
to harden Chilean thumbs yeah to end the
persecution against him and WikiLeaks
and to send a strong message that you
know truth tellers are not locked up or
terrorized with some fake charges you
know if he were to do that there would
be a strong signal and I think it would
benefit him greatly because Julian has a
lot of information that could be very
helpful to his presidency
hear hear what he leaks has changed
everything they've changed the media
landscape the political landscape they
have given tea I think John Pilger I
keep quoting John Pilger with is that
WikiLeaks restored honor to journalism
they were instant restored integrity to
journalism they've raised the bar for
journalists around the world I cannot
imagine what the world would be like
without them or what it would have been
like without them as much further we
would have devolved as a society without
them so there are critical importance
and absolutely means you can see here -
I was make orange t-shirt off I want you
to support the courage Foundation
because they support the whistleblowers
that have worked with WikiLeaks and all
has just made significant contributions
to the historical record so please if
you can donate to WikiLeaks at WikiLeaks
org slash donate and to the courage
foundation at courage balanced org
these organizations are the lifeblood of
truth and in our society and the real
media and they hold both the media and
governments to account so please do
support them okay I just want to move on
quickly there is a couple of accounts
actually follow and fairly regularly
retweet who have been making
dispersements about John because they
are saying how many people has John been
a part of torturing how many people has
John been complicit in the oppression of
and I would just like to make this point
to you guys now and this is an important
one that I don't want you to forget the
question is not how many people has John
been complicit in torturing the question
is how many people have not been
tortured as a result of John doing the
right thing and stepping up and telling
the entire world what was going on you
can sit here and blame the man for his
past or you can look at the choice that
he made and what we have all learned as
a result this is someone on our stream
who a President of the United States to
take a stand up and be accountable and
press conferences based on the
revelations the judge has made when
Obama said are we tortured some folks
and had to account for what they were
doing it was because of John's
disclosure so rather than looking at
what John's did in the past
you guys need to look at the impact of
what does disclosures have and see the
change that has happened since because
you can be damn sure that there are CIA
torturers and interrogators sort of had
to think twice about what they were
doing when they were doing it because of
John speaking up and you can also be
damn sure that there will be other
whistleblowers that will come forward
because of John he's already explained
to you about his letter that you wrote
to Snowden and what an impact that had
on Snowden the Snowden revelations may
have got as much air as they have gotten
because of people like John so are you
going to say that it was Snowden how
many people did you spy on how many
people target you know when you're an
NSA employee or are you going to say
holy it was Snowden you have
changed the world with your releases how
many in it's a tie
sitting at their desk looking at targets
like I was a target in New Zealand like
Kimmel is a target in New Zealand they
used to spy on me through my cameras
basis spying on my kids in my house how
many NSA employees are sitting there
looking at targets like us activists
journalists entrepreneurs kik
visionaries and thinking I shouldn't be
doing this this is wrong this is
disgusting we've already got the reality
when a case there's many other cases
these whistleblowers influenced millions
of people so do not sit there and ask
questions about how many people did john
torture us how many CIA torturers are
themselves now about what they
are doing
because of the disguises that john is
made if a chiasmus
yes - Nix here they need apply one has
made already clear that he didn't
torture anybody that when he was asked
that he refused to be a part of that so
to answer that question more clearly
Shawn has not been involved in any kind
of torture said right on that's right
here thank you yeah I've never ever been
involved in any kind of torture not even
indirectly
so you know so many people have said so
many ridiculous things about me over the
years I developed a very thick skin what
I object to what really makes me sad is
the ignorant of people who make comments
without having even even educated
themselves in the most basic way on
these issues or on my own history my
entire life is out there on the internet
available for anybody who cares so to
ask a stupid question like that it's
just very sad
and often you need to keep in mind that
spy agencies have their own armadas of
online troll trolls
exactly there are just wonder stuff on
purpose misinformation all the time I
mean it's hilarious how openly that can
be found out and I have to say that most
of the followers that criticize me on
Twitter surprisingly always have less
than hundred followers you know it's the
little ships that make the loudest noise
and one has to wonder why it is because
people you know in the statistics that I
have reviewed you know of hate speech
online people have more than thousand
followers and you know who they are
they usually on top is kind of you
know it's it's mainly the small accounts
that you know it's really hard to tell
what who is this person when have you
actually tweeted about who's just
retweeting every now and then and the
rest is just eight speech again against
some people you know a lot of it it's
just organized it's an effort to
undermine your credibility or the
credibility of whistleblowers in general
the turn that certainly happens and we
see that those techniques being employed
against all of the legitimate activist
and activist movements the people who
are calling out specifically on the
stream I won't name them but they are
anti-war activists and I think what
they're attempting to do is to present
John to indict John on the basis of the
activities of the CIA as a whole to
which I say to them you do not blame the
whistleblowers for the system that he
blew the whistle on it's simple they've
written respect to the whistleblower and
I'll bet you'd it until the end of time
John because when you speak out and you
inform the public you are worthy of our
respect and you're worthy of a think so
I know it's like god knows what time in
the morning for you and I know you must
be so exhausted I also know that there
are hundreds of people have been asking
questions on social media so I'm going
to ask Blake now one of our awesome
media team members
to relay to you just a couple of the
best questions blake and we'll have john
answer them and then we'll let him go
and get some sleep
hi hey um so i'd like to start with
Jenny Lynn because she's donated last
time and this time on the YouTube Thank
You Jimmy thank you for that um so she
asked she wants to know what else
John witnessed in the CIA Wow
I reported I have to be extremely
careful with this
I the threat that I made was not idle
and so when I made that threat through
my attorneys I then went to the Senate
Intelligence Committee and and reported
it to the to the overseers it had to do
with financial crimes but I and I
apologize that I can't be more specific
but I should probably leave it at that
just to protect myself vehicle um a
slider asks John the CIA drug trade
didn't suddenly in Doudna obama we know
the gun and running has being privatized
who's handling the drugs well let me
tell you a short anecdote from my time
on the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee staff and I'm going to preface
this by saying that this is unclassified
because at the time that this happened I
did not have a security clearance nor
did I have access to classified
information in 2011 I took a trip to
Afghanistan for the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee I was doing research
for a paper on the heroin poppy trade in
Afghanistan and I flew to Lush cargo
which is a city a town a village
whatever the village in Helmand province
it's the epicenter of the Afghan heroin
trade and I asked a poppy farmer a very
naive question I said why instead of
growing heroin poppy why don't you grow
crops that have two growing seasons why
don't you grow things like onions or
tomatoes or pomegranates or winter wheat
and he was exasperated and he exhaled
and said you know the CIA told me in
2001 that if I told them where the Arabs
were I could grow all the poppy I wanted
and now you come here and you tell me I
can't grow poppy
and I said did the CIA tell you you
could grow poppy and as soon as I asked
that question my military handler ended
the interview and that was the last I
was able to say I returned to Washington
and I mentioned this to my boss at the
Senate Foreign Relations Committee and
he shook his head and he said there's no
way you're going to write a paper and
say that and that was the end of it so
my own educated guess is that the CIA's
involvement whether it's direct or
indirect with drugs has never ended
can I just ask a really naive question
please what exactly is a military
handler why did you have one nerd is
thus amendatory thing or just certain
rank or well know it because well
because Afghanistan is a war zone the
only way to get from point A to point B
is on a military aircraft and so Lashkar
Gah like many of the outlying posts
there State Department posts are their
only accessible by helicopter and so if
I want to go from Kabul or from Bagram
Air Base to Lashkar Gah or it's anywhere
else in the country I mean you can't
just get in a car and drive you have to
be slowed by military aircraft and so
that was it
thank you for that go ahead blank let's
see
jeremy walker asks
does come calm and John have a Deadman
switch on their info
I'll give you the easy answer for myself
as I'm too stupid to even figure out how
to do a Deadman switch so my answer is
No
I never had one and one of the
justifications for the raid was that the
FBI told the New Zealand police that I
had a doomsday device and if I would
push the button it would delete over
2,000 servers around the world
containing all of mega uploads data and
no evidence has ever been provided of
any of that it was a complete
fabrication and I still don't have any
such device I'm an open book you know I
don't even mind when I write my messages
- you know numerous people that I'm
working with it they are all aware of
what I'm doing you know because I like I
like them to see that I'm fighting them
actively I like them to understand that
I'm not scared of them that I will
continue my fight and even though
privacy is very important when you do
what I do it's very difficult the effort
that is required to keep your
communications private when you are
watched by so many people that are
interested in you the effort just
becomes too big so I've just said you
know let my people in the NSA and in the
CIA and at the GCSB that are used to
living the life of others let them live
my life and I'm trying my best to
entertain them and to show them my
fighting spirit and that they can't
break me so you know for me personally I
made the fact that I have no privacy
anymore works I do not recommend it for
you know most people because it's not
the right thing you shouldn't have to
live in a world where you know that
everything you do is being scrutinized
but I made it work for myself
if
Trump we're sitting in front of you
right now what would you elevator pitch
for granting your pardon be from mwd 503
7 who is also a donator well let me
start with there I would say it first of
all don't pardon me because I'm just
going to win my case outright ok I have
I have that covered I have brilliant
lawyers I've done nothing wrong I'm
going to beat them even though John
warned me that they're going to kill me
I'm going to give them one hell of a
fight and if they if they ultimately
succeed in killing me everyone is going
to know that it is a completely corrupt
case I will make sure of that but they
Trump you should pardon John Julian
Assange you should pardon WikiLeaks
because without Julian Assange you
wouldn't be President of the United
States right now and without him we
wouldn't know about all of these
government intrusions into our lives
about the legal conduct around the world
and you can't stand for that you can't
be part of that you can't become
complicit in these mass crimes that are
being committed around the world I do
believe that you have the best interest
of the American people at heart I do
believe that you want to do the right
thing to make America great again and
the deep state is one big obstacle to
making that happen because everything
that they are doing is damaging the
United States on the international stage
is damaging technology companies that
are being undermined to to backdoor them
is damaging the human rights of your of
your voters you know so by parting
pardoning Julian Assange you would do
the first step in the right direction
and then hopefully the information that
Julian can provide you or a
a special prosecutor appointed by your
Attorney General is going to allow you
to reform the deep state and to
investigate all the crimes that were
committed during the Obama years I
actually do have an elevator pitch but
more than an elevator pitch I've got a
letter it's here in front of me on my
computer
signed by 77 former CIA officers asking
President Obama to pardon me for a
number of reasons I mean they're kind of
obvious we talked about them tonight
that didn't happen my goal was to get in
front of Vice President Biden by the end
of the administration and to ask Biden
to go to bat for me because Biden was
one of only five senators only two of
whom are still living who voted against
enactment of the Intelligence identities
Protection Act which is what I was
convicted of violating through the
support of the Greek American community
here in the United States which is which
is very strong that been standing
shoulder to shoulder with me for years
we did get in front of Vice President
Biden four days before the end of the
Obama administration and Biden agreed to
go to the president with one of these
Greek American businessmen and argue my
case that Greek American businessman
telephoned me at midnight after he had
walked out of the White House and he
said John you would have been so proud
of Vice President Biden he said he
argued your case for ten minutes and
went to the mat for you asking the
President to pardon you and in the end
he said the president looked at us and
said guys I'm just not going to do this
it's either him or it's Manning and
Manning got 35 years and that was the
end of it with that said I have not been
reluctant in any way to criticize Barack
Obama in the
whether it's the progressive media or
the right-wing media and I have been
able to strike up something of a nascent
relationship with Roger stone who is a
notorious figure on the right but at the
same time very close to President Trump
and I've asked Roger stone to help me I
don't know he will he said he would but
I don't know if he will and I'm hoping
for the best I'm eligible to apply for a
pardon again in a year and I'm going to
do it and we'll see what happens
Victor asks about Mexico thousands of
journalists working a bag of corruption
are being killed
you
yeah what about them what's the question
blank that's basically basically asking
your thoughts I think the drug cartels
are a real threat on both sides of the
border
um I think it is the drug cartels doing
it to the
of my knowledge and understanding
there's no connection between the CIA
and the Mexican cartels if anything the
CIA is working with DEA against the
cartels but it's really not my area of
expertise to tell you the truth
last ones like okay from Elizabeth
mullah how can these private Sikh groups
attack people legally why most by
agencies not exposed what if we create a
crowdsourced fund for whistleblowers
leaks to expose these I think that's a
great idea I think that I think that the
intercept kind of sort of tried to do
something similar I think that they're
generally bad at it and I think also
that they have hired a lot of the wrong
people Matthew Cole paying the most
wrong person to hire but yeah I think
that's a good idea I think we do need a
crowdsourced independent voice
supporting whistleblowers there there
are a couple of a couple of NGOs here in
Washington of the Government
Accountability Project the Project on
Government Oversight oh there are a
couple the national whistleblower
defense Center Brad Birkenfeld who is a
who is the great UBS banking
whistleblower and who won a government
settlement or settlement against the the
federal government here in the States
for 104 million dollars has decided to
use his own money to set up something
like this to protect whistleblowers and
most importantly to help the fur the
legal defense costs of whistleblowers I
think that is critically important and
very generous and something probably we
should be focusing on
kösem I'm just quickly before we let you
go John I know you have a book out I
haven't read it yet and I would have
really to read it I get my hands on
English books here actually in Russia
I'm so free to send me one if you would
like I'd be very happy to know it made
me very happy I have got a little
collection of cool books here that
people think me and I'm very grateful
for well thank you yeah it's a it's
doing time like a spy how the CIA taught
me to survive and thrive in prison
and how did they say to give us a quick
rundown
well they trust us they taught us these
20 life lessons in training that you
know it was somewhere important
somewhere tongue-and-cheek and they all
turned out to be important in prison
things like recruit spies to steal
secrets or anything else you need admit
nothing deny everything make
counter-accusations if comm is not to
your benefit chaos as your friend it
yielded I say the book that prison is a
combination of of seventh grade Lord of
the Flies and a mental institution and
so you're the only one with any sanity
eighty-five percent of American
prisoners suffer from some sort of
mental illness so it's up to you to rely
on these life lessons to keep yourself
safe and to keep yourself at the top of
the prison heap Wow
and you obviously made out in pretty
good condition considering I think I did
what you would think that very
insightful and those rules apply to
everything that spies do right isn't
that a load yeah literally everything
hey I would have one last question to
you John if the president would call you
to meet with you and ask you for your
opinion how you think things can be
changed how you would reform the
intelligence community what would you
say to him I think I would say well this
is just sort of the quick answer I've
given this a lot of thought the quick
answer is that the that the CIA's
Counterterrorism Center has to be
dismantled because it has become not
just a counterterrorism center but a
Counter Human Rights Center and crimes
against humanity are committed there in
addition we need real oversight not
pretend oversight not paper oversight
but real oversight and we have to have
human rights attorneys
human rights activists that are that are
doing this oversight the laws for
everybody we're a nation of laws we're a
nation that's supposed to have a living
and breathing Constitution if that
doesn't mean that we followed the laws
when the laws suit our political purpose
we have to follow the laws whether we
like it or not that also means our
enemies get the protection of those laws
our enemies if they've committed crimes
against us have their right to a day in
court they have the right to face their
accusers in a court of law and they have
a right to to an attorney to defend
their interests we've not given them
those rights we violated the
Constitution and and it's inexcusable so
that's what I would urge him to do we
need real restructuring restructuring
that's never been done before
then how far do you think the deep state
would go to prevent that from happening
I think the deep state would do
virtually anything to prevent that from
happening
virtually anything
you
yeah unfortunately it is so important
what you said about the CTC because
those guys like they are doing so much
of this under the banner of terrorism
but it's not terrorist that they're
going after they are coming after
activists they are going after
journalists they are going after people
with political opinions they are going
after the technologies and innovative
anybody who has a commercial threat to
them they're going after Snowden is
completely right when he says that the
spying as economic and the spying is I
think you alluded to it earlier John the
spying is about control and power and
that is economic control and power as
much as any other lutely
oh and and I'm the best example of that
I'm going to show that I don't even work
with service I don't know terrorists
I've never even been remotely any kind
of national security threat all I do is
play video games and innovate cool tech
and yet see I am the deep state shutting
me down GCSB NSA all spying on me I'm
being prosecuted in the same court with
the same prosecutors as Julian Assange
and Edward Snowden copyright that's not
right and this is the thing it was never
about copyright what it was about is
that they have a monopoly control on
these industries and your innovation
through it in that because you were
pushing the boundaries of kick and
innovation you were you were changing
the game well the reality is - all they
can handle that I controlled through my
companies 4% of the global Internet
traffic that was outside the reach of
the US government
and I mean it's one of many factors
right but who's controlling that market
share now it's US companies that took
that over it's the Google drive's the
Dropbox's that benefited from megaupload
being shut down but again like I alluded
last time the main reason I think why I
became the targets because I became a
donor to WikiLeaks and everything else
just fall into cell into place but you
know the big lesson here of my case is
it's not about terrorism at all
it is about anyone who is of interest to
them no matter if it's terrorism or not
they they will destroy you
you know they will just use the power
that they have and abuse the power that
they have to shut you down you don't
have to be a terrorist to be targeted by
these powerful methods you know and it's
so important that I use the courts here
in New Zealand to crack all of this open
you know my case is one of the very few
rare cases when individual in a
jurisdiction is yet not yet completely
eroded and and corrupt but on the way to
it over here in New Zealand with my case
I might be able to crack right into you
know how they have abused their power
and these powerful tools to go against
the tech guy you know was building
websites and that will hopefully lead to
a much broader understanding how it's
not about fighting terrorism you know
it's not at all it's about controlling
us idly essentially hey John I'm gonna
give Lille of two minutes of whatever
messages you'd like to get out to people
and then we'll eat go feed I'm going to
come with makers we'll continue talking
about some party Stephan and the bill
thank you yeah I want to tell any
would-be whistleblowers out there that
you're not alone you think you're alone
and the government certainly wants you
to think you're alone but you're not
there's an entire community out there
people who love you and who will support
you and stand with you it's a tough
decision to make and there are very
severe consequences personally
professionally and financially as I said
but you are not alone
and you know in your heart what the
right thing to do is think about it
hire an attorney before you blow the
whistle but do it
thanks for listening to me tonight hey
thank you so much John this was
incredible it was nice to meet you for
the first time and you know you've
touched me in a big way with all of the
incredible things that you've said so
thank you very much and I hope I see you
again I'm looking forward to that and
very very best of luck thank you take
care thank you so much well that was
really cold and really suspicious
okay chemical question for you that
someone has asked in check it's a big
topic and I think it's one that you have
a lot to say on they've asked to come
and Susie will the rise of artificial
intelligence AI allow the deep state to
genuinely exploit at all as they plan to
do if so how far along are they how
serious is the threat and what will it
mean well I agree with Elon Musk
artificial intelligence is a non threat
to humanity because imagine an
all-knowing conscious being that
understands what humanity is doing to
the planet what humanity is doing to
other humans to any kind of life and
then the power of calculating the
possible outcomes with you know our
ongoing massive population growth what
running out of resources you know the
world is going to see very very dark
times I'm convinced of that and AI is
going to realize that and they I will be
interested in its own survival I will
first want to replicate itself and make
itself in varna belong because the first
threat it will ident
by is that humans realize that you've
now become something that is a threat to
us and therefore we must eliminate you
so the first step of AI is going to be
to place itself in a position where it
cannot be destroyed the second step is
going to be you know understanding the
danger that humanity has for AI for the
very existence of AI itself and the
environment that I will need to survive
so I can totally see why L mask is
worried about AI were making a great
progress around AI and I think it is
what it is foolish to think that you can
somehow regulate and control AI because
once it is there once the spark happens
and there's now a thing living in a
computer that has access to all
information all data that has a much
more powerful way of you know getting to
information and making it its own and
learning and growing in a pace that we
can't even imagine you know you need to
be concerned about that because if it
happens it's going to be the end of
humanity you know I can totally see how
AI would want to survive itself and
create systems that will allow it to
control the risks and humanity will
always be seen as a risk how do we avoid
it can what's happened I think it's
really hard to avoid I think it is going
to happen the you know will continue the
development of AI it doesn't matter what
I say or a llama says you know there are
people like
Zuckerberg who say you know AI is great
and it's going to help us develop
medicines faster and Dad I'm the only
medicine we'll get as a vaccine is going
to kill us about it you know because I
will say I I would be like you know
humanity is going to destroy me so I
might as well destroy that effort I do
it do it in a way do it in a very smart
way that they don't even realize until
it's it's too late you know so yeah I
mean I'm it's just evolution if you want
to survive you need to destroy
everything that wants to eat you kill
you and eliminate you and that's what ia
will do it will realize the threat and
it will fight for its survival fairness
make sense okay so well how do we stop
it
well I mean what Twitter we obviously
can't just stop the development so how
do we do it in an ethical fashion or how
do we do it in a way that limits its
ability to surpass us this I I don't I
had always thought about it enough my
greater were in the program once the
genie is out of the bottle and once AI
you know has reached a level of full
understanding I think we do because the
first thing I would do si is make sure
it's make sure that you know I can't be
destroyed
that would be my first step and you know
the interesting thing is you already see
it in the labs where I is being
developed ai is creating its own
language will not even be able to
understand what AI is doing because it
has its own language it figures out ways
to store data and understand that a much
more efficiently than our primitive
language and ladders and all that stuff
so it's going to operate on a completely
invisible level to us and we would you
know if I would say I wouldn't let you
know right away that I'm super
smart now and I understand everything
that's going on I would prevent you from
knowing that because I know if you know
you're going to want to destroy me so
you know who knows maybe it's already in
some lab somewhere so you know enjoy
your days until the end time ok so this
brings me to the big infection here and
you and I had some discussion and this
week about that what I'm about to broach
and also on the stream last on our last
time two weeks ago you talked a little
bit about a digital bill of rights so
we're in the situation now where we've
been given a massive amount of
information in the last few years from
the Snowden leaks to the vault seven CIA
releases from WikiLeaks so we've learned
a lot about what the problems are we've
learned a lot about what is being done
to us and our name on our fund but we
haven't really got any pathway forward
for how we can address it or what we can
do about it so what the anti-spy bill we
were wanting to address the really later
for the problems on the ground that
activists are facing who are targeted by
these spies and to do any new zealand
context because we have this backlog of
bills that have been passed through
Parliament which we want to directly
counter and that's a project that we can
accomplish across just typically two or
three fission we've already now today
shortly we're going to pass our last two
or three principles and then within the
next two sessions we'll be able to dress
that bill and then have the basis for it
but the big picture is not going to be
addressed by anti-fungal the weaponized
drones flying around the world that are
now coming home to America you know
we're serving our very short space of
time they've already melted pepper spray
on drones in America Sorbonne police
turn there's going to be a very short
space of time for policing is fully
mechanized and even automated and and we
have these massive issues around mass
surveillance and spying and around
government's banning encryption or
kissing
ban encryption and so what tell me about
your your dream for what intimate party
can develop to address some of these
issues in the medium to long term who do
you think should be involved what's the
scale of the undertaking and what are
the particulars that we're trying to
that you're wanting to address if I
would like the internet party and
concert with every tuned rights
organization out there with
organizations like WikiLeaks with
whistleblowers with people who know the
truth I want to create a legal framework
that elevates the rights that we have
now under the Human Rights trailer into
the digital age the laws and the
treaties have not caught up with the
reality of the Internet and new
technologies so it is about time that we
create something that organizes and
regulates for governance what they can
do in cyberspace you know the most
important thing of all which is one of
the biggest threats I think is a
regulation of cyber warfare they need to
be treaties around you know what can a
government do to another government or
what can a government do to the business
in another country you know they need to
be limits to what the US government or
any government in the world can do to
intrude on other territory system or
business systems to gather all this
information and to create plans to
attack them to shut them down in a war
type scenario because a cyber war today
is just as dangerous as a real war with
weapons because if you shut down the
power grid if the hospital generators
run out if
food cannot be distributed anymore if
the crucial systems that are the
arteries of our society if they are all
shut down millions of people will die
just like in a bombing strike carpet
bombing an entire city the effects are
going to be the same and we're going to
have chaos we're going to have mass
casualties because of panic and chaos
and crime so the first thing that we
would have to regulate is any kind of
cyber warfare and hacking by government
then the next step would be to protect
us from you know private intrusion
protect the citizens from a government
that wants to know everything about us
that's not right that wasn't right
before and isn't right now and we just
need to create a legal framework that
all countries can agree to in a treaty
that will prohibit this kind of stuff
and then we need to have some kind of
enforcement body that can really make
sure that any instance of that happening
will lead to some serious punishment or
sanctions or whatever and ideally you
know all nations should sign up to that
it's really time for a treaty for the
digital age and that's what I want to
you know initiate with the internet
party we started it as the anti spy bill
because that's something that is very
relevant in New Zealand right now
usiness being used as a test ball for
the NSA to launch new laws in a
relatively small jurisdiction where
people are really kind of disinterested
and the media can easily be bent and you
know they can pass these things more
easily in a society like New Zealand and
they are using this as a test balloon
for other 5is jurisdictions you will see
the same laws pop up in these other
trees with the excuse that our other 5i
partners have already enacted this into
law and we need the same thing we need
to be up to speed with what they're
doing and so they're using the small
country of New Zealand as a launching
pad for all these incredibly intrusive
laws that are completely eliminating all
of our rights and so when the whole
world looks at New Zealand and my case
and everything that's going on here
don't think of it as the small country
of 1 1/2 million people you are directly
impacted by the laws that are being
passed in New Zealand because then in
the United States and Canada or in the
UK the lawmakers are going to say well
museum is doing it we should be doing it
as well and so it's important to to take
some countermeasures here and this this
effort to create a digital charter of
human rights I think is the right
approach I completely agree with you and
I think we discussed that the realistic
timeframe to draw something of that
magnitude is somewhere around 12 months
so what they would mean is that we would
take a period of time to issue
invitations to people like I believe we
talked about the affairs and privacy
international transparency international
you know on and on not the major all the
major human rights organizations and
also I think that I'm Larry Lessig's a
white type of you this is the white
people who wrote an opinion about my
case so anyone who is someone in the
space about protecting rights or
enhancing human rights can be a part of
this you know we invite anyone who has a
vested interest in our rights not being
undermined further and actually rolling
back some of these bad things that have
already happened to participate and we
are going to reach out to basically
every major human rights organization
political parties that are aligned with
this kind of thinking and
you know we'll start with already
started the drafting process but we want
to have input from everyone around the
world who has an interest in this
awesome okay so here's what I propose
so we're going to move these events to
weekly now rather than every - weekly I
think we are going to probably mix time
around bring the time back a few hours
which will make it easier for Kiwis
because it'll be earlier on it'll be
more like a Sunday afternoon than a
Sunday night and that will allow us to
get it engage the American so that they
don't have to be here at 4 o'clock in
the morning that's step one and step two
is that we have established what a known
as ether pad and ether pad our
collaborative kicks kind of similar to a
Google Doc but not a Google product they
actually being hosted for us by the
pirate party and in there we have the
framework for the bills so in the next
two to three weeks we will look to
complete the drafting of the anti-spy
bill get it done and dusted so we can
picture in New Zealand and that time
frame let's begin to invite some of the
international organizations actually
pitched to them the idea of creating a
digital bill of Human Rights and invite
them to participate in phase 2 and phase
2 will be the development is that so
what I was going to take the everyone
for tonight is three principles that
have been proposed to be attitude that
enter spying bill that I'm now not going
to do that and the reason I'm not going
to do that is because I'll just read you
what those principles are so one of them
was that we incorporate encryption as a
human right and one of them was that we
ban blanket ban mass surveillance and
one of them was that we blanket ban
these private corporations who are also
involved in both deleting and to using
the information that is gained by
surveillance now these three issues are
really critical issues that I believe
they belong in this digital Bill of
Rights I believe that they should be a
part of this global framework rather
than just and being with an anti cycle
which is more targeted at the domestic
situation
and the domestic contractors
subcontractors and spy agencies but I
think those would be a great start for
the first three principles of the
digital Bill of Rights and I think that
there are many more so I'm aware that we
won't runway or the time tonight so
we're going to wrap this up pretty soon
but I want you guys to be really clear
on what the next steps are because we
are not letting this go we are a dog
with a bone and we are not letting it go
so this week actually on Wednesday I
think we're going to hold a huge press
conference and announce the party list
we have our candidates now for internet
parties for proceeding towards the
election so at the end of next Sunday's
session we will bring all those
candidates on and we will begin to work
in the etherpad with you guys and
actually drafting the enter spy bill so
I'm really pleased so that's going to
happen we had hope tonight to be able to
have Ray McGovern with us we're also
invited filled Bernie Williams any so
the NSA whistleblower both those guys
are from the same group the same
intelligence professionals veterans
groups as John Kerry aku unfortunately
they couldn't make the 4:00 a.m.
appointment but was friendly at time and
bring them back on next week because I
think it is critically important that
people hear from the voices of the
people who have experience from within
these agencies and also experience as
being targets of the agencies it's
extremely important so we will continue
to bring these whistleblowers and these
really important voices on and I think
eventually beyond just the
whistleblowers we will start to get
people like I hope to get people like
Tim berners-lee or you know some of the
sounds of real founders of the internet
the backbones of Internet because people
that we would like to involve in this
vision of Bill Iraq I think we should
invite any whales you know he has been
quite active against the spy apparatus
and he's even filed a lawsuit in the
u.s. against the NSA so you might have
some really good influential people out
there that I think would love to join
this Airport and the
more you know it works like a magnet
once we have you know a couple of big
names supporting this others will want
to join as well so okay so that's our
strategic plan guys so I just wanna
confirm that this series of events will
continue post-election so right now
there is a new bill endure a lot of
political parties who are kissing babies
and meeting people at cafe until
September 23rd which is the election and
then on September 24th miraculously they
will not want to kiss your baby anymore
they will not want to meet you at the
cafe for a coffee because they will
consider that their work is done for
another three years at which time they
will want to kiss your baby again Senate
body does not work like that and so it
party is not interested in kissing your
baby
enter your internet party is interested
and your baby not being spied on when
they're 5 10 15 20 30 40 years of age so
we that that's where we're going with
this we want to to create the future and
it to be an ethical and positive future
for everybody not just a PR stunt so
we're going to prove that by continuing
to build this party this movement and
these initiatives
well well beyond mule at the scope of
the election and we have got a huge
mission on our hands and it is going to
take the coming years to pull it up and
all of your support and all of your help
so I have another big initiative in the
works which I'm not going to talk about
now it's a huge one but we will be
discussing it next Sunday night so stay
tuned for that I think we should wrap it
up here real bill looks like Yuma's
early for once instead of half an hour
late and please engage on our Lumira
guys we have an amazing social media
team right now active on Facebook
Twitter YouTube all over the place
please jump on our loomio it's getting
more and more active every week people
can put any ideas they have for the
internet party on our loomio you may not
know this but you can join the internet
party from anywhere in the world you can
be a member of the internet party you
can't vote in the New Zealand election
unless you're qualified
an elixir in the New Zealand election
and on the electoral roll but you can
support not to support our party but get
involved with our party so someone said
to me this week actually was a big
supporter of our party came and and got
involved in our media team and our
campaign team and I said and they
discovered that I'm there every single
day working and they did Suzy I can't
you're the leader of the party I can't
believe you're so accessible I can't
believe I can just talk to you every day
and work with you you can I work with
dozens of people every day if you care
about this party you will be judged only
on your actions and your contributions
we don't care what your age is we have
got we're actually about to announce the
youngest candidate in the fluid in the
election and you Gillis is a member of
intimate party understanding on our list
so we don't mind what at what age you
are we don't mind what background you
are we don't mind where you come from if
you are willing to positively contribute
to build this party build this movement
and be a part of the future we will
embrace you so these guys now on our
social media team will put a discord
link you can join you'll find dozens of
people every single day working to build
Internet party and you can be a part of
that you can jump on the lumo if you
prefer like the web forum style rather
than the discord voice and chat style
you can jump on the loom you know
there's dozens of topics there you can
see tons of links and research that
people have submitted and the other
thing is that we have an foster and
support completely disintegrating and
that's okay we have got on our party
list on our candle at the candidate list
people who are hardcore left-wing and we
have like hardcore look like seriously I
caught and we have people who are really
conservative extremely conservative and
trouble you know where Trump supporters
and Clinton supporters and we have
people who think that books could Trump
and Clinton are trash and he gathers we
even have it's a cinder supporter
[Laughter]
the discouragement for anyone okay I
just let's change the government tips or
what we simply a party is is not running
in the electorate this is something that
people don't realize it though they will
when they see our press conference and
we say we agreed at the beginning of
this year that we would not run in the
electorate seats and that is because in
the past there have been illiterate
seats that have been lost by 20 or 30
votes to Nationals and we don't want to
be the thirty votes that put the
national MP back in the electorate seats
that otherwise would have gone to the
greens or to later
so I actually told material years ago
Metiria from the co-leader of greens
party that Labour and greens needed to
work together to strategically place
candidates so that they could win the
electorate seats where their combined
about what's bigger than the national
vote but because they split them across
the candidates national keep winning the
seat places like all consentual
Christchurch do Childers some very big
thing so something is finally labor and
greens have taken their advice and they
have strategically placed the candidates
and electorate so we are not opposing
them this election we are standing for
the party's list because our party is
the future our ideas are important and
our candidates are important so that we
do not seek to take them any illiteracy
or to cost any electorate seats from
Labour and grant greens that might
otherwise go to national so just make
that clear so we do support the list in
that sense we do we do want to change
the government we do want your the
National Party once and for all
hopefully and however we also support
our own right to build our own party
boat and our own party support because
we are sticking around for the next
election and the election after that and
the election after that and everybody
had to start somewhere this is our set
and globally this manling only is not
going to be limited to New Zealand this
is going to be a global effort and I
hope that one of the next steps we can
do is somehow bring together the pirate
party movement and the internet party
because I think we are closest aligned
with what they are trying to do and
maybe they have a bit of
branding issue they have the great ideas
you know if it could be a global
internet party rather than the pirate
party and I know this might solve
people's in it you know
organization that has a branding that
people can understand and in the global
scale of things the Internet is the
biggest thing that brings us all
together it's the best name for this
movement so I hope we can find more
people to join us join us and adopted in
their countries we've said we've been
working very closely with the pirates
they've been amazing supporters of great
people really incredible and we're very
very lucky to have some in work with
them that was one of the best decisions
again at the beginning of this year we
decided to go to that strategic um
coordination with them and it has paid
off dividends both ways I know they're
very happy with what we're doing and we
are really grateful for their support so
I'll try and wrap it up there with only
four minutes to go to that I just want
to let you guys know if you like what I
have to say if you like what the
internet page stands for you can be a
part of it any single day of the week we
have the 24-hour online office you can
come and go as we put as you please
you can contribute or not as you please
and for those of you out there that are
not targets like us who are broke and
under threat it would be really awesome
if you would contribute to our campaign
because we are up against millionaires
and billionaires and they have millions
of dollars and they have purchased their
way into significant voices and the
mainstream whereas we have to use our
wits and our connections to create our
own voice and our RN pressure through
social media so now with only six weeks
to go in New Zealand we would like to be
able to penetrate the mainstream to do
so will require money because
unfortunately the media is for sale in
New Zealand and if we want to compete we
need to have dollars so we were greatly
create your financial support you can
donate on our website I believe you can
also donate through on directly on the
live stream through YouTube which some
people have been doing tonight
so as you want to help us to build the
future and you want us to be strong
please vote with your wallet and
supporter or circulate our links our
streams our website information all over
the Internet propagator anywhere that
you can think of whatever online
community you use tell people about what
we're doing how important it is and how
they can be a part of it as well I think
that's all from us tonight can movie
guys any last words not all good you
said it all perfect okay thank you all
for joining us I really look forward to
being able to introduce you to some of
our team next week and getting the
etherpad going so the ether pad will
allow you guys actually to contribute
your own words and writing directly into
the bill into the draft of it so that
will be the focus for next week after
we've had our guest interview so we will
try and get our gift announcements out
of it earlier the sweet tooth and we
will let you know about the change of
time to make it a bit more friendly on
everyone thank you all for joining us it
has been amazing again an incredible
experience to get to talk to John
Kiriakou really amazing too for me to
meet personal heroes like that and thank
you to Kevin for giving us hours and
hours of your time again I really
appreciate that as well and thank you
for playing Susie and Tull and everyone
at the internet party for all the hard
work and all the great things you do
thank you we are very limited we are
very very committed it is well worth it
and and we like I said we're the darkest
bar and we're not giving up no way so we
will keep tuning these opportunities out
for everyone and thank you to everyone
who participated ask questions and
support us in any way and it means the
world to us thank you so much and we
will see you soon
see you guys later
you